#### Patrick J. Brown

pjbrown05@gmail.com | 612-814-2303 | Eden Prairie, MN

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-brown-9a3348b5

GitHub: <a href="https://www.github.com/pj-brown">https://www.github.com/pj-brown</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://pj-brown.github.io/PatrickBrown">https://pj-brown.github.io/PatrickBrown</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Hardworking problem solver with an artistic aptitude, excellent collaborative and communication skills, and an eagerness to learn. Recent graduate of UMN's coding boot camp with a background in fire sprinkler systems design, I have worked on projects small and large (e.g. Life Time Fitness, Edina, MN) individually and as part of a team.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Java | jQuery | VS Code | Node.js | Git | MongoDB | Mongoose | MySQL | Sequelize | Express React | Firebase | JSON | Heroku | MVC | DOM | OOP | API | Microsoft Office | MERN Full Stack | Passport

#### **PROJECTS**

Dish Tracker | https://github.com/pj-brown/caps | https://pj-brown.github.io/caps/

- Role: Frontend/Backend
- Dish Tracker was designed to help remember dishes you have ordered from nearby restaurants
- Technologies: Geolocation, USRestaurantMenu API, local storage, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Farmanger | https://github.com/pj-brown/Farmanger | https://whispering-ocean-01229.herokuapp.com/

- Role: Project Manager/Frontend/Backend
- Farmanger was created for backyard/CSA farmers to manage and track produce grown and the land it is grown on
- Technologies: MySQL,

## HuddleUp | https://github.com/pj-brown/huddleup | https://vast-inlet-67112.herokuapp.com/

- Role: Frontend/Backend
- HuddleUp's intent was to deliver a team management application for a coach or manager of a sports team
- Technologies: React, Firebase, MySQL

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Lifesaver Fire Protection**

Golden Valley, MN April 2018 - April 2020

Designer

• Designed residential, commercial, and mixed-use wet and dry fire suppression systems for new and existing buildings with both plastic and steel pipe

- Created construction documents for permit and installation including material lists, hydraulic calculations, and data submittal packages
- Developed work processes with design team to implement uniformity and standardization across all projects
- Coordinated with pipe fitters and multiple trades to improve design, avoid conflicts, and reduce rework
- Surveyed new and existing job sites to verify design and accurately order stock and fabricated materials
- Peer reviewed submittal drawings and material lists for errors and optimization
- Provided direct technical support to field as well as architects, general contractors, and subcontractors

UponorLakeville, MNDesign TechnicianDecember 2014 - March 2018

- Designed residential fire suppression systems for new construction and existing buildings
- Created construction documents for permit and installation including material lists and hydraulic calculations
- Worked closely with team members to develop best practices, review code changes, and improve workflow
- Designed projects ranging from 200 to over 20,000 ft<sup>2</sup> including townhomes, builder models, and custom homes

### **Proformance Manufacturing**

Lone Rock, WI

Lead CNC Operator

March 2011 - July 2012

- Created packaging for completed customer orders ranging from one to ten custom windows
- Applied mechanical repairs and maintained equipment for cutting operations
- Experienced with cutting processes, forklift and truck-trailer operation, lamination, adhesives, glass handling and quality control, and inventory management
- Prepared Documented Work Instructions as well as current-state evaluations and health and safety recommendations
- Supervised factory floor work for one to two employees for quality control and training

#### **EDUCATION**

### **University of Minnesota School of Professional Studies**

Remote

Certificate MERN Full Stack Web Dev

# **Hennepin Technical College**

Eden Prairie, MN

Associate of Applied Science Engineering CAD Technology

#### **Southwest Technical College**

Fennimore, WI

Certificate CNC Setup/Operator